I've learned a lot of things on the way to
amassing nearly 4 million followers on
social media.
But the most important lesson
was the one that got me to start a
brand-new YouTube channel from scratch,
despite my original channel having over
430,000 subscribers,
and even to start a brand-new
Instagram account,
although my original one had 1.4 million
followers.
It's why I barely use my TikTok account
with 1.8
million followers.
It's why I've pretty much abandoned
Twitter, and I've
started going all in on LinkedIn. And
that lesson is I built a large
audience of followers,
and I should've been optimizing for a
large audience of
buyers. I only realized this
when we released a product called
Nootonic, myself and
Chris Williamson. Chris
is mega famous now on YouTube
and Instagram, and he's
friends with the Alex Hormozis
and David Goggins and Jordan Peterson.
But I brought him in on this project
when he had 200,000 followers, and now
he's stuck with me. But
when we did the launch video, there
were a lot of people
out there saying, "You're a grifter." "Oh,
you've sold out." And I got the same
thing last week when I released the
announcement of an investment I made into
a
UK-based TRT company.
And I definitely fell into a trap of just
trying to be
famous in some respects.
And it wasn't actually
that I want to be famous.
It was about getting status from certain
accomplishments, such as having a
Silver Play Button or a Gold Play Button.
Silver you get for 100,000.
Gold you get for a million.
Although I'd done some impressive things,
"Sunday
Times" number one best-selling author
three times.
By the way,
a lot of people say "Sunday Times"
best-selling author.
You get to say that
if you're in the top 10.
You only get to say number one
if you're number one.
Not that I'm bitter about it or anything.
But when I looked at your Mike Thurstons,
your Matt Does Fitnesses, there were so
many people that had that million subs.
And it's crazy.
Even on the way to one, two, three,
400,000 subscribers, so many more
podcasts and commercial opportunities find
their way to you.
If we were to look into it of like a
ranking order,
TikTok gets the least respect.
You have two million on TikTok,
people don't care.
Instagram's a really strong middle ground.
But YouTube is the holy grail.
I almost feel like a YouTube subscription
is worth the same as five followers
because people on Instagram will follow
here and there.
But on YouTube,
it's a real calculated decision whether
or not we want our feed to
be curated with your videos. So what
is the key lesson that I've got for you?
It would be to not do this. There
are videos that you can do that you just
know are going to be viral.
You could social hack, for instance.
Take someone incredibly famous,
put them in your thumbnail,
make the video about
them, although the lesson
is more of your own story.
Or it could be reacting to pop culture.
So on my main channel,
the big ones would've been Logan Paul's
Prime, a couple
cheap shots at Logan Paul,
taking down Athletic Greens for being
rubbish, in my
honest personal opinion. The list goes on.
But the problem is the people
that then engage and follow you on those,
they're not
buyers. They're people
that just like seeing companies get taken
down.
Some of them are buyers.
But whilst on my little journey of trying
to grow an
account big enough to be respected by my
peers, I was building what can only be
described as a subprime audience.
Sure, there's some gold in there,
but it's inflated with subprime
people that don't really champion you,
what you want to do,
and what you're trying
to get out of life,
what products you want to build to market.
It's very much a vanity metric. And
if the majority of your audience
are built up
of these subprime contingents, then
when you go to drop a product,
you're going to
get a negative reception to it.
So I started a new Instagram.
I started a new YouTube. Now, obviously,
that was going to suck from the beginning.
You're starting from scratch.
But any of you out there that
are thinking about
doing a similar thing,
it almost makes the whole process a little
bit more
enjoyable. You know you're the underdog.
You know you're fighting against the odds.
But something really powerful happens.
Although your engagement
and your views are much lower,
those people actually care.
And if you keep your content niche to the
problems of the people you are solving,
and you don't make the mistakes I did by
trying to go famous and jumping on any bit
of pop culture just to get the followers
to grow to a point that I was like, "Oh my
God,
I'm going to get the Gold Play button."
Although on paper you might have a
smaller audience,
that could be a red hot nucleus to
what you need. And do you know what?
A great example of this would be Adam
Sullivan, EBT.
When I met him,
he had 500,000 Instagram followers,
which is pretty good.
No real YouTube presence,
no real Facebook presence, no real TikTok
presence. I went to his house, which
was one of six houses, which was a
small mansion. He
was telling me about the $11 million house
that he had just
bought.
He picked me up from the airport in the
Lamborghini Urus.
We went out drinking,
where he let the waitress pick any tip she
wanted, and I mean any tip.
So I paid her $300.
But then he thought it would be funny to
tip the taxi driver $1,000 to go from
Broadbeach to Broadbeach. He then,
for banter, knew that my friend
Durin liked his shoe collection
and started grabbing Jordans
and throwing them
into the lake outside his mansion because
it was funny.
Although Adam doesn't have a massive
audience at this point, not even
over a million, he
was making more money than ever before
because he had a red
hot audience of people
that bought his stuff.
And they bought his stuff because they
bought into his brand.
They bought into who he was.
And I won't lie to you.
I had him blocked on social media for
three years because I thought he
was a prick.
Then I realized I
was probably just a little bit jealous.
So I unblocked him,
and now we're really good friends,
and we actually talk at
least every week. When I
was studying in Ed Lawrence's course,
there was a guy on
there that made 33,000 US dollars from 800
views.
And it was that kind of awakening you need
that you are way better off having less
views on a video
that convert to people
that actually buy your products and
services. Because there
are so many people out there with massive
audiences that
are broke and that
are stressing about the amount of views
they get on the next
video so that YouTube will give them a
good AdSense pay packet so they can pay
their editors and survive another month.
This is the formula you need.
Every piece of content has to work
backwards from someone's problem.
The reason for this video
is I actually think there
are some creators out there
watching this that
are pivoting somewhere in their career.
You might have an audience,
maybe subprime, maybe not,
but of people that
you won over as a different person in a
different stage of your life.
And you're thinking, "Do I just try
and bombard this audience with the new
stuff
I'm doing,
where most of them won't be interested,
which is going to absolutely
tank the algorithms?" Because
if nine out of 10 people go,
"This isn't for me," the
algorithm can't distinguish
that from just being a bad piece of
content.
And I think deep down you know
that you need to set up some new channels.
You need to start fresh.
You need to swallow your pride
and your ego and
get back into it, get back on the horse,
and grow the exact same thing that you did
before. And you know
that it could look a bit embarrassing
that you put loads of
effort into a video
that only gets 350 views.
But unfortunately,
I'm here saying not only
is this the start, not only is this
inevitable, but it
was one of the best decisions I've ever
made.
I love my smaller channels.
I love my smaller YouTube.
I'm excited over the fact
that I might get a second Silver Play
button.
But the second I feel that emotion, I go,
"What are you doing, brother?
That's not the goal." Remember,
it's not about getting a big channel.
It's about getting a big amount of people
that are going to buy your stuff.
And maybe you just needed to hear
that from me. And that
is the very strategy.
The video is only about a problem
that you have that I try and solve.
If you go look at nine out of 10 of my
videos on this channel,
every single one has
a problem you are facing
that I want to help you solve.
If you make your content around just that,
you may not get the biggest audience.
You may not be the most viral person.
You may not have a video
that gets millions of views.
And you may never even see a Silver Play
button.
But that is the new meta for getting ahead
in business.
Solve people's problems.
Have a dense prime audience.
That's all you need.
Don't get distracted
and waste years trying to be famous,
to get big followings,
to have good vanity metrics.
Because at the end of the day,
you can't buy first class,
lay down on a plane,
build the ultimate lad pad,
or buy a new car with the amount of likes
that you've
got or the amount of followers
or story views you got.
The only way you can do that
is with buying customers.
So why not optimize for those?
When it comes to converting people
that watch your
content into buying customers, it
is imperative that you send them to a
well-optimized landing page.
So I'm going to put a link in the
description to get
that.
And if you're not interested in making
your conversions better, you should
watch this video right here because the
boffins at YouTube reckon it's going to
really help you. Speak to you in a bit.
Bye-bye.